<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Dotahook Blog</title>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <description>DotA 2 news and commentary from the Dotahook team.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 21:33:02 +0800</pubDate>
    
      





      <item>
        <title>Bloodcyka Dominates Meta | The Dotahook Blog</title>
        
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/25/bloodcykaDominatesMeta/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/07/25/bloodcykaDominatesMeta/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://johnygall.github.io/assets/articleImages/bloodSeeker.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blood money well spent&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bloodseeker, or as some prefer to call him, Bloodcyka, is rocketing back into the pro scene after a long absence brought upon by the popularity of the Vici Gaming deathball followed by the dark days of HOHO HAHA. We were recently blessed with a complete overhaul to Bloodseeker’s skills, upgrading the blade-wielding red Sonic from a mere pubstomper that capitalized on lack of coordination to a speedy teamfighting beast who combos well with powerful nukers, enhancing their damage with Bloodrage to vaporize enemy heroes with a single strike. Many will remember with fondness the early days of Bloodseeker’s new kit, which allowed Bloodrage to affect global spells like Zeus’s Thundergod’s Wrath and Nature’s Prophet’s Wrath of Nature with ridiculous results highlighted in several videos &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pCJMYUFMB5k&amp;amp;&quot;&gt;like this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, those days are over, but Bloodseeker’s shortage of weaknesses make counterplay more frustrating than fun. His sustain from Bloodrage makes him difficult to zone when every last hit provides more than a tango’s worth of health. Even with constant right-click harass, he just needs to continue last-hitting and he’ll be topped off again. With all of his bonus damage and a Quelling Blade, it’s nearly impossible for him to lose his lane. He doesn’t need much gold, either. Just a few levels and he packs a huge punch. . His mobility is rarely an issue as Thirst gives him the insane speed he needs to hunt down fleeing heroes, and the same passive also gives him tons of extra damage. What he really needs is attack speed, which he gets from Power Treads and Sange and Yasha and turns into a disable through Skull Basher. Rupture is especially aggravating as it forces immediate rotations or the ruptured hero to attempt to teleport home, provided they aren’t something with high mobility like Storm Spirit or Ember Spirit. With a little help from a disabler, early Ruptures make for easy kills on isolated heroes. For teams with cores that typically take a while to come online like Spectre, the constant ganks (due to the low cooldown on Rupture) are especially punishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His Dotabuff stats are especially telling. His win rate has steadily risen (though it hasn’t yet reached “pubstomp “ levels like Leshrac) and his pick rate climbed 10 percent in the last month as players realizehow well he’s suited for this patch. Soon he’ll be contesting Pudge for top dog. . The changes to gold gain in the current patch make ganking more profitable than farming, so other carries just can’t compete with the rate at which he acquires his core items while their farm is repeatedly disrupted. Note how his best matchups are against farm-intensive cores such as Spectre, Weaver and Anti-Mage in addition to heroes that rely on slows for crowd control like Omniknight and Undying. Since his strongest matchups are against traditional pubstompers (Abaddon, Omniknight, Undying, Spectre, and Silencer), he is often a reliable choice, punishing greedy team compositions especially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His weaknesses? Heroes that can outmaneuver a Bugatti (Storm Spirit, Puck, Ember Spirit) tank his Rupture (Alchemist, Morphling, Axe), or teleport away (like Io, Nature’s Prophet and Tinker). Unfortunately, most of the heroes that are good counters to Bloodseeker are either difficult to play (Earth Spirit, Oracle and Io) or simply ill-suited for the current mid-game meta (Alchemist, Morphling and Lone Druid). Picking a counter to Bloodseeker like an illusion spammer often means opening yourself up for other weaknesses that can be exploited with heroes like Leshrac, which explains why he is much likelier to be banned than picked in the pro scene. It’s a testament to Bloodseeker’s power in this patch that even at the highest tier of play, few people want to have deal with his bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 10:05:58 +0800</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      





      <item>
        <title>When Are We Getting Pit Lord? | The Dotahook Blog</title>
        
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/20/whenAreWeGettingPitLord/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/07/20/whenAreWeGettingPitLord/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://johnygall.github.io/assets/articleImages/pitlord.png&quot; alt=&quot;Warlock used to have a weak turn 7 until he came around&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With TI5 around the corner, many people expect the release of one of the two heroes that have yet to be added to the game. At TI4 we saw the release of Techies, a hero that quickly found its place at the bottom of the hero list sorted by win rate with something around 40%. In a year’s time, he has been buffed repeatedly until he is where he is today: one of the most popular (and hated) heroes in the game and with a win rate hovering around 53%. As to what possessed Icefraud to buff the hero to the point where EG.Sumail immediately conceded defeat after queuing against a skilled Techies player and proceeded to feed until he lost, we will never know. The point is, don’t expect much from the new heroes. Give them a little time and a few buffs, and suddenly you’ll be groaning every time you see one on the enemy team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re currently waiting on two heroes to be added, Abyssal Underlord (formerly Pit Lord) and Arc Warden. What we do know is that Abyssal Underlord is definitely coming sooner than Arc Warden, as his model has already been added to the game, and what would TI be without a new hero reveal? Assuming we do get Abyssal Underlord soon, I think it would be helpful to go over what we know about this hero already. Keep in mind I never played this hero during my brief stint in DotA All-Stars, so anything written here is purely conjecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about stats. His strength and intelligence growth are decent, but his agility gain is very low, so there’s not much chance of him building into a right-click carry later on. His goal is merely to stay close to the team fight and not die, making sure that his aura affects as many enemy heroes as possible.
His first skill, Firestorm, is a repeated magical AOE nuke that hits six times over six seconds with added burn damage for each hit. It will do impressive damage to anything unfortunate to remain inside its radius for the full duration of six-seconds and not much else, so this skill seems to be more effective as wave-clear rather than a team fight skill unless used with a long-duration disable like Chronosphere or Reverse Polarity. It can also provide decent area denial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His next skill, Pit of Malice is a short-duration AOE root that goes through spell immunity and can’t be dispelled. You throw a pit on the ground that lasts seven seconds and if enemies find their way into it, they are damaged and can’t move, but they can still do everything else. It seems pretty lackluster on its own, but good for setting up a follow-up stun or AOE like Firestorm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His passive, Atrophy Aura, makes Abyssal Underlord a considerable threat later in the game as it provides a debuff to all enemies in a modest radius. This aura has two effects: the first is similar to a slightly more powerful Vengeance Aura reducing enemy damage by a certain percentage (with a Vengeful Spirit on your team you could potentially lower enemy attack damage by almost 80%) while the second effect has some similarity to Elder Titan’s Astral Spirit, causing every enemy unit that dies under this effect to buff Abyssal Underlord’s damage. The low radius of this passive suggests that this hero has some carry potential if he goes full tank mode, allowing him to walk up to enemies and punch them in the face while they do significantly less damage in return. Also, it would increase his farming speed in the jungle. Needless to say, this damage debuff is significant enough to the point where the enemy will make this hero their number one priority to eliminate from the equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly we come to the most insane spell, Dark Rift, basically an AOE Relocate that can pull your entire team to a location anywhere on the map, provided that there is a building or lane creep to teleport to. It could be used for some interesting ganking tactics, but in most games I expect to see this used more for split-pushing and ratting. Looking at his skills altogether, split-pushing seems to be the most obvious way of playing the hero, with some possibility of becoming a tanky anti-carry in the late-game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 10:05:58 +0800</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
